[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
&gt;&gt; 欢迎大家
Last year, we introduced Metal
去年 我们介绍了第二代
2, which includes new ways for
Metal 技术 包括了新的用于
the GPU to drive the rendering
图形处理器（GPU）来驱动
pipeline.
渲染管线的方式
This year, we're introducing
今年 我们将带来
even more new and exciting
更多新鲜的 激动人心的
features to solve common game
技术来解决
development challenges.
常见的游戏开发中的挑战
My name is Brian Ross, and
我叫 Brian Ross
together with my colleague,
我将和我的同事
Michael Imbrogno, we'll explore
Michael Imbrogno 一起来展示
new ways to make your
一些新的方式来使你的
applications better, faster, and
App 更好 更快
more efficient.
并且更加有效率
But first, I want to talk about
但是首先 我想要谈一谈
some of the challenges that I'm
那些我们试图去
trying to help you solve.
帮助你们解决的问题
Your games are using an
现在大家的游戏
ever-increasing number of
使用了越来越多的
objects, materials, and lights.
对象 材质 和光线
Games like Inside, for example,
比如说 游戏“深处”（Inside）
use a great deal of special
使用了大量的特效
effects to capture and support
来捕捉和渲染
the mood of the game.
游戏带来的的情感
Making games like this that
制作这样能让你全身心沉浸进去
truly draw you in is challenging
的游戏是十分有挑战性的
because it can require efficient
因为它需要高效的
GPU utilization.
图形处理器（GPU）利用率
At the same time, games are
同时 游戏也需要
requiring more and more CPU
越来越多的 CPU 周期
cycles for exciting gameplay.
为激动人心的游戏玩法做支撑
For example, games like Tomb
举个例子 游戏古墓丽影
Raider that features
不仅拥有
breathtaking vistas and
令人惊叹的风景和
highly-detailed terrain, but, at
极其细致的地形
the same time, they're also
他们还在
managing complex physics
AI 中管理
simulations in AI.
复杂的物理仿真
This is challenging because it
这十分具有挑战性因为
leaves less CPU time for
预留了更少的 CPU 时间来实现渲染
And finally, developers are
最终 开发者们将把
taking AAA titles like Fortnite
3A 级游戏比如像来自 Epic Games
from Epic Games, importing them
的《堡垒之夜》移植进
to iOS so you can run a
iOS 中 然后你们就
console-level game in the palm
可以在手中玩游戏机级别的游戏了
This is a truly amazing feat,
这是一个非常惊人的举动
but this also leaves us with
但是它给我们带来了
even more challenges, like how
更多的挑战 比如说像
to balance battery life with a
如何平衡电池的寿命
great frame rate.
和帧率之间的关系
So now, let's look at how Metal
现在 让我们来看一看 Metal 技术
can help you solve these
是如何帮助我们解决这些挑战
Today, I'm going to show you how
今天 我将要展示给你们如何
to harness parallelism on both
在中央处理器（CPU）和图形处理器（GPU）
the CPU and the GPU to draw more
上利用并行来绘制
complex scenes.
更复杂的场景
We'll also talk about ways to
我们也将会谈到如何对堆
maximize performance using more
栅栏和事件进行
explicit control with heaps,
更加精确的控制
fences, and events.
来最优化性能
And then, I'm going to show you
然后 我将要展示
how to build GPU-driven
如何使用我们的最新功能
pipelines using our latest
参数缓冲区和间接命令缓冲区
features, argument buffers and
来构建图形处理器（GPU）
indirect command buffers.
驱动的管线
Now, while all these API
虽然所有的这些 API 提升
improvements are key, it's
都很关键
equally important to understand
但理解支持他们运行的
the underlying hardware they run
底层硬件也十分重要
So the next section, my
所以接下来
colleague Michael is going to
我的同事 Michael 将要给
show you how to optimize for the
你们展示如何针对
A11 to improve performance
A11 来进行优化以达到提升性能
extend playtime.
延长游戏时间的目的
And finally, I'm really excited
最后 我很高兴
that we're going to be joined by
来自 Epic Games 的 Nick Penwarden
Nick Penwarden from Epic Games.
将会加入我们
He is going to show us how
他将给我们展示
they've used Metal to bring
他们是如何运用 Metal 技术使
console-level games to our
游戏机级别的游戏可以在
devices.
我们的设备上运行
So let's get started.
让我们开始吧
Harnessing both CPU and GPU
利用中央处理器（CPU）和图形处理器（GPU）
parallelism is probably the most
并行可能是
important and easiest
你可以做到的最重要
optimization you can make.
也是最简单的优化
Building a command stream on a
在单线程上构建
single thread is not sufficient
命令流已经不能满足现在的要求了
The latest iPhone has 6 cores,
最新款的 iPhone 拥有 6 个内核
and the iMac Pro can have up to
而 iMac Pro 拥有多达 18 个内核
So scalable, multithreaded
因此 可扩展的多线程
architecture is key to great
架构是我们所有设备
performance on all of our
拥有卓越表现的关键
devices.
Metal 技术是为了
multithreading.
多线程而设计的
I'm going to show you 2 ways how
我将先向你们展示在中央处理器（CPU）
to parallelize on the CPU, and
进行并行操作的两种方法
then I'm going to close this
接下来我将展示 Metal 科技是
section by showing you how Metal
如何在图形处理器（GPU）上
could automatically parallelize
自动进行并行的
for you on the GPU.
作为本节的结尾
So let's set up an example of a
我们来举一个典型的
typical game frame.
游戏架构的例子
With a classic, single-threaded
使用经典的单线程
rendering, you'd [inaudible]
渲染 [ 音质不清晰 ]
build GPU commands and GPU
你会将图形处理器（GPU）命令和
execution order into a single
图形处理器（GPU）执行依次在单个
command buffer.
命令缓冲区内构建
Typically, you're then having to
通常情况下 你将会把这个时间
fit this into some small
匹配到适合你的
fraction of your frame time.
帧时间当中
And, of course, you're going to
而且当然 你将得到
have maximum latency because the
最长的延迟时间
entire command buffer must be
由于整个命令缓冲区必须在
encoded before the GPU can
图形处理器（GPU）可以使用之前
consume it.
进行编码
Obviously, there's a better way
显然 有更好的方法可以来
to do this, so what we're going
做到这一点
to do is we're going to start by
所以我们要做的就是
building in parallelism with the
和中央处理器（CPU）一起
CPU.
进行并行构建
Render and compute passes are
渲染和计算传递
the basic granularity of
是 Metal 技术中多线程操作
multithread in Metal.
的基本粒度
All you need to do is create
所有你需要做的
multiple command buffers and
就是创建多个命令缓冲区
start encoding each into
并在单独的线程上
separate passes on a separate
分别对不同的通道进行编码
You can encode them in any order
你可以按照任何你希望的顺序
you wish.
对它们进行编码
The final order of execution is
最终的执行顺序
determined by the order they're
取决于它们添加到
added to the command queue.
命令队列的先后
So now, let's take a look at how
所以 现在让我们来看一看
easy this is to do in your code.
在代码中这是多么容易实现
So you can see this is not a lot
你可以看到这并不需要很多代码
The first thing that you're
你要做的第一件事是
going to do is create any number
从队列中创建
of command buffers from the
任意数量的命令缓冲区
Next, we're going to define the
接下来 我们将通过使用
GPU execution order upfront by
enqueue 接口来提前定义
using the enqueue interface.
图形处理器（GPU）的执行顺序
This is great because you can do
这非常棒 因为
all this without waiting for the
你可以在不用等待命令缓冲区
command buffer to be encoded
首先 被编码的情况下完成所有操作
And finally, we're going to
最后 我们将为
create separate threads and
每个部分创建
caller encoding functions for
单独的线程和调用编码函数
And that's it.
这就是全部了
That's all you have to do.
这就是你需要做的内容
It's really fast, it's really
它非常快速 非常
efficient, and it's really
高效 而且非常简单
So now, let's go back to the
所以现在 让我们回到
previous diagram and look at
前面的图表 看一下另一个例子
So as you can see, we did a
就像你所看到的 我们能够在
pretty good job parallelizing
中央处理器（CPU）上执行很好的
these on the CPU, but what if
并行操作 但是如果
you have 1 really long rendering
你有一个非常长的渲染通道呢
So in cases like this, Metal has
在这种情况下 Metal 技术
a dedicated parallel encoder
使用了一个专用的并行编码器
that allows you to encode on
它允许你在多个线程上
multiple threads without
进行编码 并且无需
explicitly dividing up the
明确划分
render pass or the command
渲染通道或命令缓冲区
So now, let's look at how simple
所以现在 让我们来看一看它
this is in your code.
在你的代码里有多简单
It looks a lot like the previous
它看起来非常像之前的例子
The first thing you're going to
你要做的第一件事就是
do is create a parallel encoder.
创建一个并行编码器
And from that, you create any
并且从这个并行编码器中
number of subordinate encoders.
创建任意数量的从属编码器
And it's important to realize
很重要的一点是意识到
that this is actually where you
这实际上就是你
define the GPU execution order.
定义图形处理器（GPU）执行顺序的地方
Next, we're going to create
接下来 我们将创建
separate threads and encode each
单独的线程并单独对
of our G-buffer functions
我们的每个 G 缓冲（G-buffer）函数进行编码
And finally, we set up a
最后 我们会设置一个
notification so that when the
通知 当线程
threads are complete, we call
完成时 我们可以在
end encoding on the parallel
并行编码器上调用结束编码
encoder.
这就是全部了
That's all you have to do to
这就是你并行化渲染通道
parallelize a render pass.
所需要做的全部内容
It's really fast, and it's
它非常快速
really easy.
而且非常简单
So now that I've shown you 2
现在我已经向你展示了两种在
ways to parallelize on the CPU,
中央处理器（CPU）上并行化的方法
now let's see how Metal can
现在让我们看看 Metal 技术
parallelize for you
如何在图形处理器（GPU）上
automatically on the GPU.
为你进行自动并行化
So let's look at the frame
所以让我们先从头看一下
example from the beginning and
一个框架示例 然后看一看
see how the GPU executes the
图形处理器（GPU）如何执行这个框架
Based on the capabilities of
基于你平台的功能
your platform, Metal can extract
Metal 技术可以通过
parallelism automatically by
分析数据相关性
analyzing your data
自动提取并行性
Let's look at just 2 of these
现在让我们看一看这些相关性
So in this example, the particle
在这个例子中 粒子模拟会
simulation writes data, which is
写入数据 而这些数据稍后
later used by the effects pass
将会被效果用来
to render the particles.
渲染粒子
Similarly, the G-buffer pass
类似地 G 缓冲（G-buffer）通道
generates geometry, which is
生成几何图形 稍后将会通过
later used by the deferred
延迟着色过程
shading pass to compute material
来计算材质的明暗
lighting.
所有这些信息都
Metal to automatically and
允许 Metal 技术自动
cheaply identify entire passes
并且便宜地识别
that can run in parallel, such
可以并行运行的整个通道
as using async compute.
例如使用异步计算
So you can achieve parallelism
所以你可以在
and async compute for free on
图形处理器（GPU）上获得免费的并
the GPU.
行和异步计算
It's free because Metal doesn't
它是免费的原因是
require you to do anything
Metal 技术不需要你
special on your part.
做任何特别的事情
So I think we all love getting
我认为我们都喜欢
free optimizations on the GPU,
在图形处理器（GPU）上获得免费优化
but sometimes you as a
但有时候作为一名
developer, you may need to dive
开发人员 你可能需要走得
a little bit deeper.
更远一点
For the most critical parts of
所以对于你代码中最关键的部分
your code, Metal allows you to
Metal 技术允许你
incrementally dive deeper with
逐步控制一些更深层次的内容
For example, you could disable
例如 你可以禁用
automatic reference counting and
自动引用计数并
do it yourself to save on CPU
自己执行以节省中央处理器（CPU）时间
You could also use Metal heaps
你也可以使用 Metal 堆
to tightly control allocations
来真正低消耗地严格控制分配
And Metal heaps are complemented
并且 Metal 堆可以
by fences and events, which
由栅栏和事件补充 这可以让你
allow you to explicitly control
明确控制图形处理器（GPU）
the GPU parallelism.
的并行操作
Many of your games are using a
许多游戏使用
lot of resources, which can be
大量的资源 这可能需要花费高昂的代价
Allocations require a round trip
分配需要不断和 OS
to the OS, which has to map and
进行双向沟通 OS 系统必须映射
initialize memory on each
并初始化每个请求的内存
If your game uses temporary
如果你的游戏使用临时
render targets, these
渲染目标 这些
allocations can happen in the
分配可能发生在
middle of your frame, causing
你的框架中间 造成卡顿
Resource heaps are a great
资源堆是解决
solution to this problem.
这个问题的好方法
Heaps also let you allocate
堆也可以让你提前从
large slabs of memory from the
系统中分配大量内存
And from those, you can later
然后 你就可以在
add or remove textures and
这些内存上添加或删除纹理
buffers from those slabs without
和缓冲区 而无需进行
any costly round trip.
任何昂贵的双向沟通
So starting from a case where
因此 从分配
you allocate 3 normal textures,
3 种常规纹理的情况开始
Metal typically places these in
Metal 技术通常将这些放到
3 separate allocations, but
3 个单独的分配中 但是
putting these all instead into a
将这些全部分配到
single heap lets you perform all
单个堆中可以让你
memory allocation upfront at
提前在堆创建时执行
heap creation time.
所有的内存分配
So then, the act of creating
那么创建纹理
textures becomes extremely
将会变得非常低耗
Also, heaps can sometimes let us
另外 堆有时可以
use the space more efficiently
通过使分配更紧密
by packing allocations closer
来更有效地使用空间
So with a traditional model, you
因此在使用传统模型时
would deallocate textures,
你将取消分配纹理
releasing pages back to the
将页释放回系统
system, and then reallocate,
然后重新分配
which will allocate a new set of
重新分配将再一次分配
textures all over again.
一组新的纹理
With heaps, you deallocate and
通过使用堆 你可以取消分配和
reallocate without any costly
重新分配资源 而无需任何昂贵的
round trip to the OS.
和系统进行的双向沟通
Finally, heaps also let you
最后 堆也可以让你
alias different memory resources
互相分享不同的内存资源
This is really helpful if your
这在当你的
game frame has a lot of
游戏框架有很多
temporary render targets.
临时渲染目标时非常有用
There's no reason for these to
没有理由让这些目标
occupy a different memory all
不断地占用不同的内存
the time, so you could alias and
所以你可以替换入口
save hundreds of megabytes.
并省下数百兆字节
Now, the faster allocations in
现在 在替换入口的方式中
aliasing are great, but it's not
分配速度更快 但在
entirely free when it comes to
涉及相关性跟踪时 它并不是
dependency tracking.
完全没有影响的
Let's return to our frame
让我们回到
example for a better
框架示例来进行
explanation.
更好的解释
With heaps, Metal no longer sees
当使用了堆时
individual resources, so
Metal 技术就看不到单个的资源
therefore, it can't
因此它不能
automatically identify the read
自动识别通道之间
and write dependencies between
的读写相关性
passes, such as the G-buffer and
例如示例中的
deferred shading pass in our
G 缓冲（G-buffer）和延期着色通道
So you have to use fences to
所以你必须使用栅栏
explicitly signal which pass
来明确地标记哪个
produces data and which pass
通道产生数据 哪个通道
consumes the data.
消耗数据
So in this example, the G-buffer
在这个例子中 G 缓冲（G-buffer）
updates the fence, and the
更新了栅栏 并且
deferred shading waits for it.
延迟着色等待着它的结果
So now, let's take a look at how
所以现在 让我们来看一看
we could apply these basic
如何在你的代码中应用
concepts in your code.
这些基本概念
So the first thing that we're
我们要做的第一件事
going to do is we're going to
就是将这个
apply this to our G-buffer and
应用到我们的 G 缓冲（G-buffer）和
deferred shading example.
延迟着色示例中
First, we're going to allocate
首先 我们将
our temporary render target from
从堆中分配我们的
the heap.
临时渲染目标
This looks just like what you're
这看起来非常像
probably already doing today
今天在分配纹理时可能
when you allocate a texture.
已经做的事情
Next, we're going to render into
接下来 我们将渲染
that temporary render target.
该临时渲染目标
And finally, update the fence
最后 在分段阶段
after the fragment stage
完成后更新栅栏
This will ensure that all the
这将确保所有数据
data is produced before the next
在下一个通道使用它
pass consumes it.
之前生成
So now, let's switch gears over
现在 让我们切换到
to the deferred shading pass.
延迟着色过程
Now, we're going to use this
我们将使用
temporary render target to
这个临时渲染目标来
compute material lighting.
计算材质的明暗
Then, we're going to wait for
然后 我们将等待栅栏
the fence to make sure that it's
来确保它在我们使用
been produced before we consume
之前已经生产完成了
And finally, market is aliasable
最后 资源是可以替换的
so that we can reuse this for
这样我们就可以重新使用它来
other operations, saving
进行其他操作
hundreds of megabytes.
节省数百兆字节
So now that we've talked about
现在我们已经讨论了
how to parallelize and optimize
如何通过明确的控制
performance with explicit
来进行并行化和优化性能
control, this is great, but what
这非常棒 但是
if you want to put the GPU more
如果你想让 GPU 更多地进入
into the driving seat?
参与这个过程呢
So let's talk about GPU-driven
那么接下来我们来讨论一下 GPU 驱动的管线
pipelines.
你们的游戏正在将越来
more of the decision logic onto
越多的决策逻辑
the GPU, especially when it
转移到 GPU 上 尤其是当在
comes to processing extremely
处理包含数千个
large data sets or scene graphs
对象的超大型数据集
with thousands of objects.
或场景图时
With Metal 2, we've made another
Metal 二代技术使
really important step forward in
我们在 GPU 驱动管线
our focus on GPU-driven
方面又迈出了重要一步
Last year, we introduced
去年 我们引入了
indirect argument buffers,
间接参数缓冲区
allowing you to further decrease
这可以进一步降低
CPU usage and move a large
CPU 使用率 并将大部分
portion of the workload to the
工作量转移到 GPU 上
This year, we're also
今年 我们再一次引入了
introducing indirect command
间接命令缓冲区
buffers, and this will allow you
这将允许你将
to move entire rendering loops
整个渲染循环转移到 GPU 上
So first, let's briefly recap
首先 让我们简要回顾一下
the argument buffer feature.
参数缓冲区的功能
An argument buffer is simply a
参数缓冲区就是像大屏幕上
structure represented like this.
呈现的这样一个结构
Previously, these would have
以前这里
only constants, but with
只有常量 但有了
argument buffers, we can have
参数缓冲区 我们可以拥有
textures and samplers.
纹理和采样器
Before, these would have to have
在一切之前 这些必须具有
separate shader bind points.
独立的着色器绑定点
So since this structure, you
但是由于这种结构
have all the features of the
你可以在你的处理中
Metal shading language at your
使用 Metal 着色语言的所有
disposal, so it's really
功能 因此它非常
flexible and really easy.
灵活并且非常简单
You could do things like add
你可以执行像添加
substructures, or arrays, or
子结构或数组甚至
even pointers to other argument
是指向其他参数缓冲区的指针的操作
You could modify textures and
你可以修改纹理和
samplers, creating new materials
采样器 在 GPU 上创建
on a GPU without any CPU
新材质并且无需 CPU 参与
Or you can make giant arrays of
或者 你可以制作巨大的
materials and use a
材质数组 并且使用
single-instance draw call to
单实例绘图调用
render many objects with unique
来呈现许多具有独特属性的对象
So argument buffers allow you to
参数缓冲区允许你将
offload the material management
材质管理卸载到
onto the GPU and save valuable
GPU 上并节省宝贵的 CPU 资源
But this year, we're putting it
但今年 我们把它稍微扩展了
a little bit, extending it a
一点 再稍稍
little bit more.
扩展了一点
We started by adding 2 new
我们开始加入 2 个新的
argument types.
参数类型
This includes pipeline states
它们包括管线状态和
and command buffers.
命令缓冲区
Now, these are used to support
现在 这些将用于
our brand-new indirect command
支持我们全新的
buffer feature.
间接命令缓冲区功能
With indirect command buffers,
通过间接命令缓冲区
you could encode entire scenes
你可以在 GPU 上编码整个场景
On the CPU, you only have a few
在 CPU 上 你只有几个线程
threads available for rendering,
可用于渲染
but on the GPU, you have
但是在 GPU 上
hundreds or even thousands of
你拥有数百甚至
threads all running at the same
数千个可以同时运行的线程
With indirect command buffers,
通过间接命令缓冲区
you can fully utilize this
你可以充分利用这种
massively parallel nature.
大规模的并行性质
Also, indirect command buffers
此外 间接命令缓冲区是
are completely reusable, so you
完全可以复用的
could spend the encoding cost
因此你可以只花费
once and reuse it again and
一次编码成本 然后不断重复使用它
And since an ICB is a directly
由于 ICB 是一个可直接
accessible buffer, you can
访问的缓冲区 因此你可以
modify its contents at any time,
随时修改它的内容
like change the shader type, or
例如更改着色器类型
the camera matrix, or anything
或相机矩阵 或者其他
else that you might need to
任何你可能需要更改的内容
And of course, by moving your
当然 通过将渲染
rendering to the GPU, you remove
转移到 GPU 上
expensive CPU and GPU
你可以移除昂贵的 CPU
synchronization points that are
和 GPU 同步点 这些
normally required to hand over
同步点通常需要提交数据给它们
So let's take a look at an
让我们来看一个例子
Here is a typical game frame.
这是一个典型的游戏框架
The usual rendering loop has a
一般的渲染循环有
few common stages.
常见的几个阶段
First, you walk your scene graph
首先 你通过浏览
to determine which objects you
场景图来确定哪些对象
need to render.
需要被渲染
You probably use frustum culling
你可能使用
to determine what objects are
视锥体剔除来确定
within the view frustum.
视锥体内的物体
Some of you might use a more
你们中的一些人可能会
complex solution that accounts
使用更加复杂的方法来解决
for occlusion.
遮挡问题
Also, level of detail selection
此外细节选择的程度自然
naturally occurs at this stage.
而然地产生在这个阶段
Only once you encode and submit
只有当你编码并
your command buffer will the GPU
提交命令缓冲区后 GPU 才会
start to consume it.
开始使用它
More and more games are moving
越来越多的游戏正在将
the process of determining
确定可见对象的过程
visible objects onto the GPU.
转移到 GPU 上
GPUs are just better at handling
GPU 在处理最近游戏中出现的
the growing scene complexity of
越来越复杂的场景方面
the latest games.
做得更好
Unfortunately, this creates a
不幸的是 这会在你的框架中
sync point in your frame.
创建一个同步点
And the, it makes it so that the
而且它使得 CPU 不能对
CPU cannot encode draw calls
绘制调用进行编码直到
until the GPU produces the data.
GPU 产生数据
It's extremely difficult to get
在不浪费宝贵的
this right without wasting
CPU 和 GPU 同步时间的情况下
valuable CPU and GPU time on
完成该任务是极其困难的
With ICBs, the benefits are
ICB 的好处是巨大的
Not only can you move the final
你不仅可以将最后的处理
bits of processing to the GPU,
转移到 GPU 上 还可以
you naturally remove any sync
自然移除任何
points required to hand over the
交换数据所需的
data and you improve your CPU
同步点 并且提高 CPU 和 GPU
and GPU utilization.
的利用率
At the same time, you reduce
同时 你可以把
your CPU overhead to a constant.
CPU 开销降至一个常量
So let's look at the encoding in
所以让我们来看一下
a little bit more detail.
编码的细节
I'm going to start by expanding
我将首先使用前面的
on our previous example and look
例子来看一看
at the massively parallel nature
只有 GPU 可以提供的
that only the GPU can provide.
大规模并行化
We could begin with the list of
我们从剔除调度中的
visible objects and LODs coming
可见对象列表和 LOD 开始
Also, keep in mind that we're
另外 请记住
utilizing the power of argument
我们正在使用参数缓冲区的能力
So in this case, each element
所以在这种情况下
has a pointer to the actual
每个元素都有一个
properties, so we don't need to
指向实际属性的指针 所以
store everything in the same
我们不需要将所有内容都存储在
buffer.
同一个缓冲区内
This solution saves us a lot of
这种方式为我们
memory and performance, and it's
节省了大量的内存和性能
because we only build a very
这是因为我们只构建了
small list of information.
一小部分信息
The actual argument buffer
实际参数缓冲区
contains several levels of
包含几个级别的几何细节
This includes position, vertex
它们包括位置
buffer, index buffer, and a
顶点缓冲区 索引缓冲区
material argument buffer.
和材质参数缓冲区
For rendering, we only select 1
关于渲染 我们只选择每个对象的
of these LODs per object.
多个 LOD 中的一个
The actual encoding happens in a
实际的编码发生在
compute kernel, and we encode
一个计算内核中 我们把它
into an indirect command buffer.
编码成一个间接命令缓冲区
Each thread of the compute
计算内核的每个
kernel encodes a single draw
线程都编码一个绘制调用
So we read the object with all
所以我们读取对象
of its properties, and we encode
具有的所有属性 并将它们编码
these into the ICB.
到 ICB 中
There's a couple of details
这里有一些值得
worth noting.
注意的细节
You can think of an ICB as an
你可以把 ICB 视为
array of render commands.
一系列渲染命令
A render command consists of a
一个渲染命令包含
pipeline object with shaders,
带有着色器的管线对象
any number of buffers, and a
任意数量的缓冲区
draw call.
和绘制调用
Next, an ICB is built for
然后 ICB 是为并行
parallelism, so you could encode
而构建的 因此你可以同时进行编码
concurrently and out of order.
并且不用担心顺序
And lastly, we kept the API very
最后 我们使 API 保持
simple, so it's just like what
简单 所以以上这些操作
you might be doing today on the
就像你今天在可能在 CPU 上所做的一样
Another thing -- each command
另外 每个命令
could have different properties
可以有不同的属性 甚至不同的
and even draw types.
绘制类型
So this is a really, really
因此 这对于许多人
significant step forward from
可能在其他地方
all the flavors of indirect
看到的所有
rendering that many of you may
间接渲染 都是十分
have seen elsewhere.
重要的一步
Now, let's take a look at how we
现在 我们来看看如何在
can do this in your code.
代码中执行此操作
So this is how easy it is to
编码一个绘图调用
encode a draw call.
就是这么容易
The first thing you're going to
你要做的第一件事就是
do is select the render command
使用你的线程 ID 得到索引
by index using your thread ID.
并通过索引来选择渲染命令
Then, we're going to set the
然后 我们要设置属性
So in this example, we're
在这个例子中
setting a shader with a pipeline
我们设置了一个具有管线状态的着色器
state and then a separate buffer
然后为几何和材质设置了
for the geometry and material.
单独的缓冲区
And finally, this is how you
最后 这是你编码一个绘图调用
encode a draw call.
一个绘图调用的方式
Thanks to the Metal shading
由于 Metal 着色语言
language, encoding on the GPU is
在 GPU 上编码真的变得
really, really simple.
非常 非常简单
Even though this is in a compute
即使是在计算着色器中
shader, this looks just like
这看起来就像
what you're already doing on the
就像你今天在可能在 CPU 上所做的事一样
Now, let's look at 1 more
现在 我们再看另一个例子
Here are some of the basic
这些是创建 编码和
things you need to do to create,
执行 ICB 所需做的
encode, and execute an ICB.
一些基本工作
To create it, you first fill out
你首先填写一个状态描述来创建它
The descriptor contains things
状态描述包含
like draw types, and inheritance
绘制类型 继承
properties, and per-stage bind
属性和每层的绑定计数等内容
This describes the way that the
这描述了间接缓冲区的
indirect buffer will behave.
行为方式
When it's time to encode the
在对 ICB 进行编码时
ICB, you simply create compute
你只需创建
encoder and call dispatch just
计算编码器和调用调度
like what you've been doing
就像你已经在做的一样
Once the ICB is encoded, you can
一旦 ICB 被编码
optionally decide if you want to
你可以选择是否要优化它
When you optimize it, you remove
当你决定优化它
all the redundant state, and the
你会删除所有的冗余状态
end result is a lean and
最终的结果是
highly-efficient set of GPU
一组精简而高效的 GPU 命令
Now, once the ICB is encoded and
现在 一旦 ICB 被编码
optimized, it's time to schedule
和优化 就可以安排它进行
it for execution.
执行操作了
You notice here that you could
你会注意到
actually specify the exact range
在这里你实际上可以
of commands that you execute.
指定你执行的命令的确切范围
Also in this example, we use an
同样在这个例子中
indirect buffer, which itself
我们使用了一个间接缓冲区
can be encoded with a GPU.
它本身就可以用 GPU 编码
So once the ICB is encoded, it
所以一旦 ICB 完成编码
could be reused again and again,
它就可以被一次又一次地
and the overhead is completely
重复使用 并且开销是完全
negligible.
可以被忽略不计的
So I'm really excited, but we
我非常兴奋
actually went ahead and we put
但我们还要接着往下走
together a sample so you could
我们将一个例子与代码放在一起
take a look.
以便你们可以看一下
So here you could see a number
在屏幕上
of school buses in the middle of
你可以看到一些城市中的校车
Each bus is composed of 500,000
每辆校车由 500,000
polygons and 2000 individual
个多边形和 2000 个独立部分组成
Each part requires a separate
每个部分都需要
draw call, its own material
一个单独的绘图调用 它自己的
argument buffer, index buffer,
材质参数缓冲区 索引缓冲区
and vertex buffer.
和顶点缓冲区
As you could imagine, this would
正如你想象的那样
be a lot of API calls on the
这将会有很多 CPU 上的 API 调用
CPU, but we are using indirect
但是我们在这里使用了
command buffers here, so
间接命令缓冲区
everything is being encoded on
所以一切都将在 GPU 上编码
We're also selecting the
我们也会选择
appropriate level of detail, and
合适的的细节级别
therefore, we're able to render
因此 我们可以在
multiple objects without
呈现多个对象的同时
increasing the CPU or GPU cost.
也不会增加 CPU 或 GPU 上的花费
So on the left, you could see a
在屏幕左边 你可以看到
view of the regular camera.
常规相机的视图
And on the right, we've zoomed
而在屏幕右侧
in to a single bus, so you could
我们放大了一辆校车
see the level of detail actually
你可以看到细节级别在变化
ICBs enabled us to introduce
ICB 使我们能够
another really incredible
推出另一个令人难以置信的
optimization.
优化方式
We're able to split the geometry
我们能够将几何体
into chunks of a few hundred
分成由几百个
triangles and analyze those
三角形组成的块 并在单独的
chunks in a separate compute
计算内核中分析这些块
You could see the chunks in
你可以在屏幕上看到
different colors on the screen.
不同颜色的色块
Each thread of the kernel
内核的每个线程都会
determines whether triangles are
确定三角形是否
facing away from the camera or
背对着相机 或者它们
if they're obscured by other
是否被场景中的
objects or geometry in the
其他对象或几何体遮挡
This is all really, really fast
这是真的非常快
because we've performed the
因为我们只对一个块
calculation for a chunk only and
进行计算 而不是每个
not on each individual triangle.
单独的三角形
We then tell the GPU to only
然后我们告诉 GPU
render the chunks that are
只渲染那些
actually visible.
实际可见的块
And again, let's see the
再一次 让我们看一下
side-by-side view.
屏幕左右侧的视图
The left side is your camera
左侧是相机视图
view, and the right side is
右侧是校车的
another view of the bus.
另一个​​视图
You could see the red and
你可以在右侧看到红色和
pinkish tint there.
粉红色的色调
That is what our compute shaders
这就是我们的计算着色器
determined is invisible.
所确定的不可见的部分
We never actually send this work
我们从未真正将此场景
to the GPU, so it saves us 50%
发送给 GPU 因此它可以节省 50％
or more of the geometry
或更多的几何渲染成本
Here's 1 last view showing
这是最后一个视图
which, how much this technique
它展示了这种技术 可以为你节省多少成本
So notice on the right, many of
注意右侧的画面
the buses and ambulances are
许多校车和救护车实际上
actually invisible.
是隐形的
This is really amazing.
这实在是太神奇了
I love this.
我喜欢这个
So please take a chance to
所以请尽情地探索代码
explore the code, and I hope
我希望我将来会在
I'll see this technology in some
一些游戏中看到
of your games in the future.
这种技术的应用
I think if utilized, ICBs can
我想如果你使用了它
really push your games to the
ICB 可以将你的游戏推向
next level.
更高的水平
So now, I'm pleased to introduce
现在 我很高兴向大家介绍
Michael, who will show you how
Michael 他将向你们
to optimize for the A11, improve
展示如何针对 A11 进行优化
performance, and extend
改善性能并延长游戏时间
Thank you very much.
十分感谢
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Brian.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Brian
So everything Brian's just
Brian 刚刚展示的
showed you is available for iOS,
所有内容都适用于 iOS
tvOS, and macOS.
tvOS 和 macOS
Next, I'm going to dive into
接下来 我将深入探讨
some of the new Metal 2 features
Apple 最新的 GPU A11 Bionic
for Apple's latest GPU, the A11
拥有的 Metal 二代技术
Bionic, designed to help you
的一些新功能 它们
maximize your game's performance
旨在通过减少
and extend your playtime by
系统内存带宽和降低功耗
reducing system memory bandwidth
来帮助你最大化游戏性能
and reducing power consumption.
并且延长游戏时间
So Apple-designed GPUs have a
Apple 设计的 GPU
tile-based deferred rendering
拥有切片式延迟渲染架构
architecture designed for both
这是专为高性能和低功耗
high performance and low power.
而设计的
This architecture takes
这种架构利用
advantage of a high bandwidth,
高带宽低延迟的
low-latency tile memory that
内存来消除透支
eliminates overdraw and
和不必要的
unnecessary memory traffic.
内存流量
Now, Metal is designed to take
现在 Metal 技术在
advantage of the TBDR
每个渲染通道
architecture automatically
加载和存储操作中都
within each render pass, load
自动利用 TBDR 架构
and store actions, make explicit
明确了渲染通道的
how render pass attachments move
内容是如何写入和写出
in and out of tile memory.
Tile 内存的
But the A11 GPU takes the TBDR
但 A11 GPU 进一步利用了
architecture even further.
TBDR 架构
We added new capabilities to our
我们在 Tile 的内存中
tile memory and added an
添加了新功能 并且增加了一个
entirely new programmable stage.
全新的可编程阶段
This opens up new optimization
这为高级的渲染技术
opportunities critical to
提供了至关重要
advanced rendering techniques,
的新的优化机会
such as deferred shading,
例如延迟着色
order-independent transparency,
与顺序无关的透明度
tiled forward shading, and
平铺正向着色
particle rendering.
和粒子渲染
So let's start by taking a look
让我们先
at the architecture of the A11
看一下 A11 GPU 的架构
All right.
好的 在屏幕的左边
representation of the A11 GPU.
我们有 A11 GPU 的展示
And on the right, we have system
而在屏幕右边
memory.
我们有系统内存的展示
Now, the A11 GPU first processes
现在 A11 GPU 先处理
all the geometry of a render
所有顶点阶段在
pass in the vertex stage.
渲染通道中的几何
It transforms and bends your
它将你的几何
geometry into screen-aligned,
变换并弯曲成屏幕对齐
tiled vertex buffers.
的平铺顶点缓冲区
These tiled vertex buffers are
然后这些平铺的
then stored in the system
顶点缓冲区 将会存储在系统内存中
Now, each tiled vertex buffer is
现在 每个平铺的顶点缓冲区
then processed entirely on ship
将作为碎片阶段的一部分
as part of the fragment stage.
在传输时完全处理完
This tiled architecture enables
这种平铺架构可
2 major optimizations that your
以让你的游戏免费获得
games get for free.
2 个主要优化
First, the GPU rasterizes all
首先 GPU 在使用快速的
primitives in a tile before
用于传输的内存对任何像素
shading any pixels using fast,
进行着色之前 对所有图元进行
on-ship memory.
光栅化处理
This eliminates overdraw, which
这消除了内存的透支
improves performance and reduces
从而提高了性能并
power.
降低了功耗
Second, a larger, more flexible
其次 用更大 更灵活的 Tile 内存
shaded fragments.
来存储着色片段
Blending operations are fast
混合操作速度很快
because all the data is stored
这是是由于所有数据都
on ship next to the shading
存储在着色核心旁边用于
cores.
传输的内存上
Now, tile memory is written to
现在 在所有 Tile 内存被
system memory only once for each
着色之后 每个
tile after all fragments have
Tile 内存仅被写入系统内存一次
This reduces bandwidth, which
这会降低带宽
also improves your performance
这同时也会提升你的性能
and reduces your power.
并降低功耗
Now, these optimizations happen
现在 这些优化发生在一切之下
You get them just by using Metal
你只需在 iOS 上使用 Metal 技术即可
on iOS.
得到它们
But Metal also lets you optimize
但 Metal 技术还可以
rendering techniques by taking
通过明确控制 A11 的
explicit control of the A11's
Tile 的内存来优化
tile memory.
渲染技术
Now, during the development of
现在 在 A11 GPU 的
the A11 GPU, the hardware and
开发过程中 Apple 的硬件
software teams at Apple analyzed
和软件团队分析了
a number of important modern
许多重要的现代
rendering techniques.
渲染技术
We accelerated, we noticed many
我们加速了内存
common themes, and we found that
我们注意到了很多共同的主题
explicit control of our tile
并且我们发现显式控制我们的
memory accelerated all of them.
Tile 内存 可以为所有的这些内存加速
We then developed the hardware
接下来 我们围绕
and software features together
这种显式控制的想法
around this idea of explicit
开发了硬件和软件功能
So let's talk about these
那么现在让我们来谈谈这些功能
So programmable blending lets
可编程的混合让你
you write custom blend
可以在着色器中编写
operations in your shaders.
自定义的混合操作
It's also a powerful tool you
它也是一个可以用来
can use to merge render passes,
合并渲染通道的
and it's actually made available
强大工具 实际上它可以
across all iOS GPUs.
用于所有的 iOS 的 GPU
Imageblocks are new for A11.
图像块（Imageblocks）是 A11 的新增功能
They let you maximize your use
它们通过直接用
of tile memory by controlling
着色语言控制
pixel layouts directly in the
像素布局 可以让你最大限度地
shading language.
利用 Tile 的内存
And tile shading is our
Tile 的着色是我们
brand-new programmable stage
全新的可编程舞台
designed for techniques that
它是专为需要混合图形
require mixing graphics and
和计算处理的技术
compute processing.
而设计的
Persistent threadgroup memory is
持久线程组内存是
an important tool for combining
组合渲染和计算的
render and compute that allows
重要工具 它允许
you to communicate across both
你通过绘制和调度
draws and dispatches.
进行通信
And multi-sample color coverage
多样本颜色覆盖控制
control lets you perform resolve
可以让你使用 Tile 的
operations directly in tile
着色器直接在 Tile 的内存中
memory using tile shaders.
执行解析操作
So I'm going to talk to you
所以我要和你说一说
about all these features, so
所有的这些功能
let's start with programmable
让我们从可编程混合开始吧
With programmable blending, your
通过可编程混合
fragment shader has read and
你的片段着色器
write access to pixels and tile
可以读取和写入像素和 Tile 的内存
This lets you write custom
这可以让你编写自定义的
blending operations.
混合操作
But programmable blending also
但是 可编程混合
lets you eliminate system memory
还可以通过组合
bandwidth by combining multiple
多个读取和写入
render passes that read and
相同内容的渲染通道来
write the same attachments.
消除系统内存带宽
Now, deferred shading is a
现在 延迟着色
particularly good fit for
特别适合于
programmable blending, so let's
应用可编程混合 所以让
take a closer look at that.
我们仔细看一下
So deferred shading is a
延迟着色是
many-light technique
一种一般使用
traditionally implemented using
2 遍传递实现的多光技术
In the first pass, multiple
在第一遍中
attachments are filled with
多个附件填充了
geometry attributes visible at
每个像素可见的
each pixel, such as normal,
几何属性 例如法线
albedo, and roughness.
反照率和粗糙度
And in the second pass,
在第二遍中 通过对那些
fragments are shaded by sampling
G 缓冲的内容进行采样来对
those G-buffer attachments.
片段进行着色
Now, the G-buffers are stored in
现在 G 缓冲先被存储在
the system memory before being
系统内存中 然后再次在
read again in the lighting pass,
光照通道中读取
and this round trip from tile
并且从 Tile 的内存到系统内存的
memory to system memory and back
双向交流和再次回退
again can really bottleneck your
可能使你的游戏进入
game because the G-buffer track
瓶颈 因为 G 缓冲
consumes a large amount of
轨道消耗了大量的带宽
Now, programmable blending
现在 可编程混合可以
instead lets you skip that round
让你直接从 Tile 的内存
trip to memory by reading the
中读取到当前像素的
current pixel's data directly
数据 从而跳过内存的
from tile memory.
来回沟通
This also means that we no
这也意味着我们
longer need 2 passes.
不再需要 2 次传递
Our G-buffer fill and lighting
我们 G 缓冲的填充
steps are now encoded and
和光照步骤现在
executed in a single render
被编码和运行在每个渲染通道中
It also means that we no longer
这也意味着
need a copy of the G-buffer
我们不再需要系统内存中的
attachments in system memory.
G 缓冲内容的副本
And with memory, Metal's
有了内存 Metal 技术的
memoryless render target
无记忆渲染目标功能
feature, saving that memory is
对于节省内存来说真的非常
really, really simple.
非常简单
You just create a texture with a
你只需创建一个
memoryless flag set, and Metal's
带有无记忆标记的纹理
only going to let you use it as
同时 Metal 技术仅允许
an attachment without load or
你在没有进行加载或存储操作的情况下
store actions.
把它作为附件
So now, let's take a look at how
所以 现在让我们来看一看
easy it is to adopt programmable
在着色器中使用可编程混合
blending in your shaders.
是多么的容易
Okay, so here's what the
好的 这里是你的
fragment shader of your lighting
光通道的
pass would look like with
片段着色器在可编程混合中的样子
Programmable blending is enabled
当你读取和写入
when you both read and write
你的附件时 可编程混合将被启用
And in this example, we see that
在这个例子中
the G-buffer attachments are
我们看到 G 缓冲附件
both inputs and outputs to our
既是我们函数的输入 又是函数的输出
We first calculate our lighting
我们首先使用我们的 G 缓冲的属性
using our G-buffer properties.
来计算我们的照明
As you can see here, we're
正如你在这里看到的
reading our attachments and
我们正在读取我们的附件
we're not sampling them as
但我们并没有将它们作为纹理
textures.
进行采样
We then accumulate our lighting
然后 我们将我们的照明的
result back into the G-buffer,
累积结果返回 G 缓冲
and, in this step, we're both
在这一步中
reading and writing our
我们都在读取和写入
accumulation attachments.
我们的累积结果
So that's it.
这就是最后了
Programmable blending is really
可编程混合真的非常简单
that easy, and you should it
只要你有多个
where, whenever you have
读取和写入相同附件
multiple render passes that read
的渲染过程 你就应该在
and write the same attachments.
那里应用它
So now, let's talk about
所以现在我们来讨论
imageblocks, which allow you to
一下图像块（Imageblocks）
merge render passes in even more
它允许你在更多的情况下
circumstances.
合并渲染通道
Imageblocks give you full
图像块（Imageblocks）可以
control of your data in tile
让你在 Tile 的内存中完全
memory.
控制你的数据
Instead of describing pixels as
图像块允许你以
arrays of render pass
结构体的形式直接用
attachments in the Metal API,
着色语言声明像素布局
imageblocks let you declare your
而不是将像素描述
pixel layouts directly in the
为 Metal 技术的 API 中的
shading language as structs.
渲染通道内容中的数组
It adds new pack data types to
它将新的数据类型
the shading language that match
添加到与你已经使用的
the texture formats you already
匹配纹理格式的
use, and these types are
着色语言当中
transparently packed and
并且在访问着色器时
unpacked when accessing the
这些类型被透明地打包和解压
In fact, you can also use these
实际上 你还可以在
new pack data types in your
顶点缓冲区和
vertex buffers and constant
常量缓冲区中使用
buffers to more tightly pack all
这些新的数据类型来更紧密地
of your data.
打包所有数据
Imageblocks also let you
图像块（Imageblocks）还允许
describe more complex per-pixel
你描述更复杂的每个像素
data structures.
数据结构
You can use arrays, nested
你可以使用数组
structs, or combinations
嵌套结构或其组合
It all just works.
它们都可以正常运行
Now, direct control of your
现在 直接控制
pixel layout means that you can
像素布局意味着
now change the layout within a
你现在可以在通道内
pass.
更改布局
This lets you combine render
这使你可以将渲染过程
passes to eliminate system
组合起来 从而消除
memory bandwidth in ways that
系统内存带宽
just weren't possible with
而这种方式仅凭
programmable blending alone.
可编程混合是无法实现的
Let's take a look at an example.
让我们来看一个例子
So in our previous example, we
在我们之前的例子中
used programmable blending to
我们使用可编程混合
implement single-pass deferred
来实现单通延迟着色
You can also implement
你也可以使用
single-pass deferred shading
图像块实现单通道延迟着色
Imageblocks only exist in tile
图像块只存在于 Tile 内存中
memory, so there's no render
所以没有渲染通道附件
pass attachments to deal with.
需要处理
Not only is this a more natural
这不仅是一种
way to express the algorithm,
更加自然的表达算法的方式
but now you're free to reuse the
而且现在你也可以在
tile memory once you're finished
完成照明后读取
reading the G-buffer after your
G 缓冲 然后再重新使用 Tile 的内存
So let's go ahead and do that.
让我们继续
Let's reuse the tile memory to
让我们重复使用
add an order-independent
Tile 的内存来添加
transparency technique called
一个称为多层 Alpha 混合的顺序无关的
multi-layer alpha blending.
透明度技术
So multi-layer alpha blending,
多层 Alpha 混合（MLAB）
or MLAB, maintains a per-pixel,
可维护每个像素
fixed-size array of translucent
固定大小的半透明片段数组
Each incoming fragment is sorted
每个传入的片段按
by depth into the array.
深度排序加到数组中
If a fragment's depth lies
如果一个片段的深度
beyond the last element of the
超出了数组的最后
array, then those elements are
一个元素 那么
merged, so it's really an
这些元素就会被合并
approximation, approximate
所以它实际上是
technique.
一个近似的技术
Now, sorting the MLAB array is
现在 对 MLAB 数组进行
really fast because it lives in
排序速度非常快 因为它存在于
tile memory.
Tile 的内存中
Doing the same off chip would be
由于额外的带宽
really expensive because of the
和同步开销 在芯片
extra bandwidth and
上做同样的操作会变得
synchronization overhead.
非常昂贵
Now, the A11 actually doubles
A11 实际上是对
the maximum supported pixel size
上一代支持的最大像素尺寸
over your previous generation,
进行了加倍
but that's still not going to be
但这还不足以
enough to contain both the
同时包含
G-buffer and MLAB data
G 缓冲和 MLAB 数据结构
Fortunately, you don't need both
幸运的是 你不需要
at the same time.
同时使用两者
Imageblocks let you change your
图像块（Imageblocks）允许
pixel layouts inside the render
你在渲染过程中
pass to match your current
更改像素布局以符合
needs.
你的当前需求
So changing pixel layouts
改变像素布局实际上
actually requires tile shading,
需要 Tile 的着色 所以我们接下来
so let's talk about that next.
来讨论一下这个
So tile shading is the new
Tile 着色是
programmable stage that provides
新的可编程阶段
compute capabilities directly in
它直接在渲染过程中提供了
the render pass.
计算能力
This stage is going to execute a
这个阶段将会在
configurable threadgroup for
每个 Tile 上执行一个可配置的线程组
For example, you can launch a
举个例子
single thread per tile, or you
你可以为每个 Tile 启动一个线程
can launch a thread per pixel.
或者也可以为每个像素启动一个线程
Now, tile shading lets you
Tile 的着色
interleave draw calls and
可以让你交叉使用
threadgroup dispatches that
对相同数据进行操作的绘制调用
operate on the same data.
和线程组调度
Tile shaders have access to all
Tile 的着色器可
of tile memory, so they can read
以访问所有 Tile 内存
and write any pixel of the
因此它们可以读写图像块的任何像素
So let's look at how tile
那么让我们来看一看
shading can optimize techniques
Tile 着色如何优化切片正向着色等技术
So like deferred shading, tiled
像延迟着色一样
forward shading is a
切片正向着色是一种多层技术
It's often used when MSA is
我们通常会在
important or when a variety of
MSA 非常重要时
materials are needed and works
或需要各种材料时使用它
equally well for both opaque and
并且它对不透明和半透明几何图形
translucent geometry.
同样适用切片正向着色
traditionally consists of 3
一般由 3 次传递组成
First, a render pass generates a
首先 一个渲染通道生成了
scene depth buffer.
一个场景深度缓冲区
Second, a compute pass
其次 计算通道将会
generates, calculates per-tile
生成并计算使用该场景
depth bounds and per-tile light
深度缓冲区的
lists using that scene depth
每个 Tile 深度边界和光源列表
And finally, another render pass
最后 另一个渲染通道
is going to shade the pixels in
将使用相应的光源列表
each tile using the
为每个 Tile 中的像素着色
Now, this pattern of mixing
现在 这种混合
render with compute occurs
渲染和计算的模式是很常见的
And prior to A11, communicating
在 A11 之前
across these passes required
这些通道之间的交流需要系统内存
But with tile shading, we can
但是使用 Tile 着色
inline the compute so that the
我们可以将计算内联
render passes can be merged.
所以渲染通道就可以合并
Here the depth bounds and light
在这里 深度边界和
culling steps are now
光线剔除步骤被
implemented as tile shaders and
作为 Tile 着色器实现
inlined into a single render
并内嵌到单个渲染通道中
Depth is now only stored in the
深度现在只
imageblock and, but is
存储在图像块中
accessible across the entire
但却可以在整个过程中被访问
pass.
所以现在 Tile 的着色
to help you eliminate a lot of
将帮助你消除大量带宽
bandwidth, but these tile shader
但这些 Tile 的着色器的输出
outputs are still being stored
仍然存储在系统内存中
Tile shader dispatches are
Tile 的着色器
synchronized with draws, so
调度与绘制同步
that's completely safe to do,
所以这是完全安全的
but I think we could still do
但我认为我们仍然可以
better using our next feature,
使用我们的下一个功能
persistent threadgroup memory.
持久线程组内存 来使我们做得更好
Okay, so threadgroup memory is a
好的 线程组内存
well-known feature of Metal
是 Metal 技术计算的一个众所周知的特性
It lets threads within a
它使线程组内的线程
threadgroup share data using
可以使用快速的 用于传输的内存
fast, on-ship memory.
来共享数据
Now, thanks to tile shading,
现在 由于 Tile 着色
threadgroup memory is now also
线程组内存也可以在
available in the render pass.
渲染通道中使用
But threadgroup memory in the
但渲染通道中的
render pass has 2 new
线程组内存含有
capabilities not traditionally
2 个传统上不可用于计算
available to compute.
的新功能
First, a fragment shader now
首先 片段着色器
also has access to the same
现在也可以访问相同的
threadgroup memory.
线程组内存
And second, the contents of
其次 线程组内存
threadgroup memory persist
的内容在整个
across the entire life of a
Tile 的整个生命周期中都存在
Taken together, this makes a
总而言之 这是
powerful tool for sharing data
一个强大的工具
across both draws and
可以让数据在绘制和调度之间共享
In fact, we believe it's so
实际上 我们相信
useful that we've actually
这会非常有用
doubled the maximum size of
因为我们实际上已经
threadgroup memory over our
使线程组内存的最大容量翻倍
previous generation so that you
比起上一代来说
can store more of your
你可以将更多的中间数据
intermediate data on ship.
存储在传输过程中
Okay, so now, let's use
好的 现在让我们使用持久线程组
further optimize our tiled
来进一步优化我们的
forward shading example.
切片正向着色示例
So with persistence, tile, the
因此 有了持久线程组
tile shading stage can now write
Tile 的着色阶段
both the depth bounds and the
可以将深度边界和
culled light lists into
剔除光线列表写入
threadgroup memory for later
线程组内存中供
draws to use.
以后使用
This means that now all our
这意味着现在我们所有的
intermediate data stays on ship
中间数据都会保留在传输过程上
and never leaves the GPU.
并且永远不会离开 GPU
Only the final image is stored
只有最终的图像存储
at system memory.
在系统内存中
Minimizing bandwidth to system
尽量减少系统内存
memory is, again, very important
的带宽对于游戏的
for your game's performance and
性能和游戏时间来说是非常重要的
playtime.
现在 我们来看一看
easy it is to make use of
在着色语言中
persistence in the shading
使用持久线程组有多容易
Okay, so the top function here
好的 所以这里的顶层函数
is our tile shader, and it's
是我们的 Tile 着色器
going to perform our light
它将执行我们的光线剔除过程
It intersects each light with a
它将光线与
per-tile frustum to compute an
Tile 视锥相交以计算
active light mask.
主动的光掩码
The bottom function is our
底层函数是
fragment shader that performs
我们的片段着色器
our forward shading.
它执行我们的正向着色
It shades only the lights
它只使用该
intersecting the tile using that
主动光掩码遮住
active light mask.
与 Tile 相交的灯光
Now, sharing threadgroup memory
现在 在这两个着色器
across these functions is
通过使用相同类型和
achieved by using the same type
绑定点实现跨函数
and bind point across both
的共享线程组内存
That's how easy it is to take
这就是使用持久线程组有多容易
Okay, so now that you've seen
好吧 现在你已经看到了
tile shading and threadgroup
Tile 着色和持久线程组
persistence, let's revisit our
让我们再次回到
order-independent transparency
我们的顺序无关的透明度示例
Okay, so remember how I said
好的 你们还记得我说的
that changing imageblock layouts
改变图像块布局需要
requires tile shading?
Tile 着色的吗
That's because tile shading
这是因为 Tile 着色提供了
provides the synchronization we
我们需要的同步
need to safely change layouts.
而这会安全地更改布局
This means we actually have to
这意味着我们实际上
insert a tile shade between the
必须在照明和 MLAB 步骤之间
lighting and the MLAB steps.
插入 Tile 着色
So tile shading is going to wait
因此在从 G 缓冲转换到
for the lighting stage to
MLAB 之前 Tile 着色
complete before transitioning
必须等待
from G-buffer layout to MLAB
光照步骤完成
layout, and it's also going to
并且它还将把
carry forward the accumulated
光照步骤累积的
lighting value from the lighting
光照值转移到
step into the MLAB step for
MLAB 步骤中进行最终混合
Okay, so now that we've covered
好吧 现在我们已经
imageblocks, tile shading, and
介绍了图像块 图块着色
threadgroup persistence, it's
和持久线程组 现在
time to move on to our final
是时候继续讨论我们的最终
topic, multi-sample
主题 多重采样
anti-aliasing and sample
抗锯齿和示例覆盖控制
So multi-sample anti-aliasing
多重采样抗锯齿功能
improves image quality by
可通过超取样深度
supersampling depth, stencil,
模板和混合来
and blending, but shades only
提高图像质量 但每个像素
once per pixel.
只能着色一次
Multiple samples are later
多个样本稍后
resolved into a final image
将会被简单平均法解析为
using simple averaging.
最终图像
Now, multi-sampling is efficient
现在 多重采样在
on all A series GPUs because
所有 A 系列 GPU 上
samples are stored in tile
都是高效的 因为
memory, where blending and
样本存储在 Tile 内存中
resolve operations have fast
从而其中混合和解析可以
access to the samples.
快速地访问样本
The A11 GPU optimizes
A11 GPU 通过追踪
multi-sampling even further by
每个像素内的
tracking the unique colors
独特颜色进一步优化了
within each pixel.
多重采样
So blending operations that
以前在每个样本上
previously operated on each
进行的混合操作
sample now only operate on each
现在仅对每种颜色进行操作
This could be a significant
这可能是一个显著的
savings because the interior of
优化节约
every triangle only contains 1
因为每个三角形的内部
unique color.
只包含 1 种独特的颜色
Now, this mapping of unique
现在 独特颜色与
color to samples is called color
样本的映射被称为
coverage control, and it's
颜色覆盖控制 并且
managed by the GPU.
这由 GPU 管理
But tile shaders can also read
但是 Tile 着色器也可以读取
and modify this color coverage.
和修改这种颜色覆盖
And we can use this to perform
我们可以使用它来执行
custom resolves in place and in
自定义解析和快速的
fast tile memory.
Tile 内存
Now, to see why this is useful,
现在 让我们来看一看
let's take a look at a
为什么这是有用的
multi-sampled scene that also
让我们来看一下渲染粒子
renders particles.
的多重采样场景
Now, particles are transparent,
粒子是透明的
so we blend them after rendering
所以我们将在渲染我们的
our opaque scene geometry.
不透明场景几何体之后将它们混合
But particle rendering doesn't
但是粒子渲染不能从
benefit from multi-sampling
多重采样中受益
because it doesn't really have
因为它实际上没有任何可见的边缘
So to avoid the extra cost of
因此 为了避免
blending per sample for no good
无理由地混合
reason, a game would render
每个样本的额外成本
using 2 passes.
游戏将使用 2 次传递进行渲染
In the first pass, your opaque
在第一遍中 你的不透明的
scene geometry is rendered using
场景几何体
multi-sampling to reduce
将使用多重采样来渲染以减少混叠
And then, you're going to
然后 你将解决
resolve your color and depth to
关于系统内存的颜色
system memory, and we're
和深度 并且处理
resolving depth because
深度 因为之后它在之后
particles can later be included.
可以包含粒子
Then in the second pass, the
然后在第二遍中
resolve color and depth are used
使用解析颜色和
in rendering the particles
深度来渲染没有多次采样的粒子
Now, as you probably guessed by
现在 正如你现在可能
now, our goal is to eliminate
猜到的那样 我们的目标
the intermediate system memory
是使用 Tile 着色来消除
traffic using tile shading to
中间传输的系统内存
combine these 2 passes.
以便合并这两个传递
But tile shading alone isn't
但仅仅 Tile 着色是不够的
We need color coverage control
我们需要色彩覆盖控制来
to change the multi-sampling
改变多重采样率
Using color coverage control is
颜色覆盖控制功能非常强大
really powerful and really easy.
并且使用非常简单
Let's take a look at the shader.
让我们来看一下着色器
Okay, so remember that our goal
好的 请记住
here is to average the samples
我们的目标是
of each pixel and then store
平均每个像素的样本
that result back into the image
然后将该结果
block as the overall pixel
存储回图像块中作为整体像素值
Now, instead of looping through
现在 我们不是
each color, through each sample,
循环每个颜色 循环
we're going to take advantage of
每个样本 而是
the color rate capabilities of
使用 A11 的色差率
the A11 and only loop through
功能 只循环独特的颜色
To properly average across all
为了在所有样本中
samples, we need to weigh each
正确地平均
color by the number of samples
我们需要根据与其相关的
associated with it, and we do
样本数对每种颜色进行
this by counting the bit set in
加权 我们通过计算颜色掩码中
the color coverage mask.
设置的位来实现这一点
We then complete our averaging
然后 我们通过
by dividing by the total number
除以总采样数来完成
of samples and, finally, write
平均 最后将
the result back into the
结果写回到图像块中
The output sample mask tells
输出样本掩码告诉
Metal to apply the results to
Metal 技术将结果应用于
all samples of the pixel.
像素的所有样本
And since all samples now share
而且 由于所有样本
the same value, the later
现在都具有相同的值
particle draws are going to
因此后面的粒子绘制
blend per pixel rather than per
将按每个像素而不是每个样本进行混合
So that's it for sample coverage
这就是样本覆盖控制
Now, optimizing for Apple GPUs
现在 针对 Apple GPU
is really important for
进行的优化对于
maximizing your game's
最大限度地提高
performance and extending its
游戏性能并延长
playtime, but there's a lot more
游戏时间非常重要
work that goes into shipping a
但是在 iOS 平台上使用
tile in iOS, especially one
Tile 你需要做更多的工作
that's originally designed for
特别是那些最初为电脑
desktops and consoles.
和主机设计的游戏
To talk about that now and to
现在我们将谈论
put into practice what we just
这个问题 并将我们刚刚讨论过的
discussed, I'd like to bring on
内容付诸实践 我想邀请
Nick Penwarden from Epic Games.
Epic Games 的 Nick Penwarden 上台
Nick?
Nick [ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Michael.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Michael
So, yeah. I'd like to talk a
嗯 我想谈一谈
little bit about how we took a
一些关于我们如何把
game that was originally made
最初用于电脑和主机平台的游戏
for desktop and console
使用 Metal 技术
platforms and brought it to iOS
将其引入 iOS 平台的问题
So some of the technical
我们面临的一些
challenges we faced.
技术上的挑战
The Battle Royale map is 1 map.
堡垒之夜的地图是 1 张地图
It's larger than 6 kilometers
它大于 6 平方公里
That means that it will not all
这意味着它不适合
fit into memory.
全部储存在内存中
We also have dynamic time of
我们也有动态的时间
day, destruction.
流动和破坏
Players can destroy just about
玩家可以摧毁
any object in the scene.
场景中的任何物体
Players can also build their own
玩家也可以建立自己的建筑
So the map is very dynamic,
所以地图非常动态
meaning we can't do a lot of
这意味着我们不能做
precomputation.
很多预计算
We have 100 players in the map,
我们在地图上有 100 个玩家
and the map has over 50,000
地图上有超过 50,000
replicating actors that are
个复制角色 这些
simulated on the server and
复制角色在服务器上模拟
replicated down to the client.
并复制到客户端
Finally, we wanted to support
最后 我们希望支持
crossplay between console and
主机和电脑
desktop players along with
以及移动设备之间的联机游玩
And that's actually a really
这实际上是非常重要
important point because it
的一点 因为它
limited the amount that we could
限制了我们用
scale back the game in order to
缩减游戏的体量
fit into the performance
的方法来适应​​设备的
constraints of the device.
性能限制
Basically, if something affected
基本上 如果有什么东西影响了
gameplay, we couldn't change it.
游戏玩法 我们不能改变它
So if there's an object and it's
所以如果有一个对象
really small, it's really far
它真的很小 它真的很遥远
away, maybe normally you would
也许通常情况下你会剔除它
cull it, but in this case, we
但在以下这种情况下
can't because if a player can
我们不能 因为如果
hide behind it, we need to
玩家可以躲在它后面
render it.
我们就需要渲染它
So want to talk a little bit
所以现在我们来谈一谈
about Metal.
Metal 技术
Metal is really important in
Metal 技术在让我们
terms of allowing us to ship the
能够快速地运行游戏
game as fast as we did and at
以及让我们能够
the quality that we were able to
实现的游戏品质方面
achieve.
非常重要
Draw call performance was key to
绘制调用的表现是关键
this because, again, we have a
因为我们有
really complicated scene and we
一个非常复杂的场景
need the performance to render
我们需要渲染来
it, and Metal gave us that
呈现它 而 Metal 技术给了我们
performance.
这样的结果
Metal also gave us access to a
Metal 技术还让我们
number of hardware features,
能够访问许多硬件功能
such as programmable blending,
例如可编程混合
that we used to get important
这些硬件特性使我们重新获得
GPU performance back.
重要的 GPU 性能
It also has a feature set that
它还具有一套功能
allowed us to use all of the
这套功能包含了
rendering techniques we need to
可以让我们将堡垒之夜带到 iOS
bring Fortnite to iOS.
所需的所有渲染技术
In terms of rendering features,
就渲染而言
we use a movable directional
我们使用可移动的
light for the sun with cascaded
定向光来照明
shadow maps.
级联阴影贴图
We have a movable skylight
我们有一个可移动的天窗
because the sky changes
因为天空整天都在变化
We use physically-based
我们使用基于物理的材质
We render in HDR and have a
我们在 HDR 中进行渲染
tone-mapping pass at the end.
并在最后进行色调映射
We allow particle simulation on
我们允许在 GPU 上
the GPU.
进行粒子模拟
And we also support all of our
我们也支持我们所有的
artist-authored materials.
开发者自制的材质
It's actually a pretty important
这实际上是非常重要的一点
point because some of our
因为我们的
materials are actually very
一些材质实际上非常复杂
For instance, the imposters that
例如 我们用于
we use to render trees in the
高效渲染树木的东西
distance efficiently were
完全是由开发者
entirely created by a technical
在 Epic 中使用蓝图和
combination of blueprints and
材质着色器图形创建的
So in terms of where we ended
接着我们刚刚说的话题
up, here is an image of Fortnite
这里是堡垒之夜
running on a Mac at high
以高可扩展性在 Mac 上
scalability settings.
运行的图像
Here it is running on a Mac at
这在中等可扩展性下
medium scalability settings.
运行在 Mac 上的图像
And here it is on an iPhone 8
这里是在 iPhone 8 Plus
Plus.
上运行的图像
So we were able to faithfully
所以我们能够在 iPhone 上
represent the game on an iPhone
以我们在中端 Mac 上
about at the quality that we
呈现的品质完全地
achieve on a mid-range Mac.
表现游戏的质量
So let's talk a little bit about
所以我们来谈一谈可扩展性
We deal with scalability both
我们处理跨平台
across platforms as well as
和 iOS 系统的
within the iOS ecosystem.
可扩展性
So across platform, this is
因此 跨平台时
stuff that we need to fit on the
我们需要在平台上安装这一些东西
platform at all, like removing
比如从网格中
LODs from meshes that will never
移除永远不会显示的 LOD
display so we can fit in memory
因此我们可以把它
or changing the number of
放入内存或更改我们在
characters that we animate at a
特定级别上动画的
particular quality level in
角色数量 以降低 CPU 成本
Within iOS, we also defined 3
在 iOS 平台内部 我们还定义了 3 个
buckets for scalability -- low,
可扩展性 - 低
mid, and high -- and these were
中 高 - 这些
generally correlated with the
通常与不同代
different generations of
iPhone 相关
iPhones, so iPhone 6s on the low
所以 iPhone 6 使用低端
end, iPhone 7 was our mid-range
iPhone 7 使用中档
target, and the iPhone 8 and
iPhone 8 和
iPhone X on the high end.
iPhone X 使用高端
Resolution was obviously the
分辨率显然是
simplest and best scalability
我们拥有的最简单和最佳的
option that we had.
可扩展性选项
We ended up tuning this per
我们最终调整了每个设备
We preferred to use backbuffer
我们倾向于
resolution where possible --
在可能的情况下 使用后备缓冲分辨率
this is what the UI renders at
这是用户界面呈现的内容所决定的
-- because if we do this, then
因为如果我们这样做
we don't have to pay a separate
那么我们不必支付单独的
upsampling cost.
上采样成本
However, we do support rendering
但是 我们确实支持
3D resolution at a lower
以较低的分辨率
resolution, and we do so in some
渲染 3D 分辨率 在某些情况下
cases where we needed a crisp UI
我们需要一个清晰的用户界面
but had to reduce 3D render
但不得不降低 3D 渲染
resolution lower than that in
分辨率来适配
order to meet our performance
我们的性能
goals -- the iPhone 6s, for
以 iPhone 6s 为例
Shadows were another axis of
阴影是可扩展性的另一个轴
scalability and actually really
并且它非常重要
important because they impact
因为它们同时影响
both the CPU and the GPU.
CPU 和 GPU
On low-end devices, we don't
在低端设备上
render any shadows at all.
我们不呈现任何阴影
On our mid-range target, we have
在我们的中档设备上
1 cascade, 1024 by 1024.
我们有 1 个级联 1024 乘 1024 大小
We set the distance to be about
我们将距离设置为
the size of a building, so if
与近似于建筑物的大小的数值
you're inside of a structure,
因此如果你位于建筑物内部
you're not going to see light
则不会看到另一侧的
leaking on the other side.
光线泄漏
High-end phones add a second
高端设备增加了第二个级联
cascade, which gives crisper
这样可以提供更清晰的
character shadows as well as
人物阴影
lets us push out the shadowing
并让我们可以进一步
distance a little further.
推出阴影距离
Foliage was another axis of
植物是可扩展性的
scalability.
另一个轴
On low-end devices, we simply
在低端设备上
don't render foliage.
我们根本不渲染植物
On the mid range, we render
在中等设备内 我们
about 30% of the density we
呈现了我们在主机上支持的大约
support on console.
30％ 的密度的植物阴影
And on high-end devices, we
在高端设备上 我们
actually render 100% of the
实际上可以实现
density that we support on
我们在主机上支持的
console.
100％ 的密度
Memory is interesting in terms
内存在可扩展性
of scalability because it
方面很有意思
doesn't always correlate with
因为它并不总是与
performance.
性能相关
For instance, an iPhone 8 is
例如 iPhone 8
faster than an iPhone 7 Plus,
比 iPhone 7 Plus 快
but it has less physical memory.
但它的物理内存更少
This means when you're taking
这意味着当你考虑到
into account scalability, you
可扩展性时 你需要
need to treat memory
以不同的方式处理内存
We ended up treating it as an
我们最终将它
orthogonal axis of scalability
视为可伸缩性的正交轴
and just had 2 buckets, low
并且只有 2 个分类
memory and high memory.
分别是低内存和高内存
For low-memory devices, we
对于低存储设备
disabled foliage and shadows.
我们禁用了植物和阴影
We also reduced some of the
我们还减少了一些内存池
So for instance, we limited GPU
因此 例如 我们
particles to a total of 16,000
将 GPU 颗粒限制在总计 16,000 个
and reduced the pool use for
并减少了美化和纹理记忆池
cosmetics and texture memory.
的使用量
We still need to do quite a bit
但我们仍然需要
of memory optimization in order
进行相当多的内存优化
to get the game to fit on the
才能让游戏在该设备上运行
The most important was level
最重要的是
streaming -- basically, just
级别流 基本上
making sure that nothing is in
只是确保如果
memory that is not around the
对象不在玩家身边
player.
就不占任何内存
We also used ASTC texture
在大多数情况下
compression and tend to prefer
我们还使用 ASTC 纹理压缩
compressing for size rather than
并倾向于在大小而不是
quality in most cases.
质量上进行压缩
And we also gave our artists a
而且我们还为我们的
lot of tools for being able to
开发者提供了很多工具
cook out different LODs that
可以用来制作不同的 LOD
aren't needed or reduce audio
它们有些不是必须的
variations on a per-platform
或者有些可以减少每个平台的音频变化
Want to talk a little bit about
接下来我想谈一下帧速率目标
So on iOS, we wanted to target
所以在 iOS 上 我们希望
30 fps at the highest visual
可以达到最高的视觉
fidelity possible.
保真度 30 fps
However, you can't just max out
但是 你不能仅仅将设备的性能达到最大化
If we were maxing out the CPU
如果我们在整个时间内
and the GPU the entire time, the
最大限度地利用 CPU 和 GPU
operating system would end up
操作系统最终会降低
downclocking us, then we'd no
我们的速度 那么我们就
longer hit our frame rates.
不会再达到目标帧速率
We also want to conserve battery
我们同时也想要延长电池寿命
If players are playing several
如果玩家在通勤过程
games in a row during their
中连续玩几场比赛 我们希望
commute, we want to support that
在他们开始玩
rather than their device dying
之前帮助他们
before they even make it to
而不是使他们的设备死机
So for this, what we decided to
所以为此 我们决定
do was to target 60 frames per
做的是针对环境时
second for the environment, but
达到每秒 60 帧
vsync at 30, which means most of
但是在垂直同步（VSync）时
the time when you're exploring
达到 30 帧 这意味着
the map in Fortnite, your phone
大多数时候当你在堡垒之夜探索地图时
is idle about 50% of the time.
手机将闲置约 50％ 时间
Using that time to conserve
我们利用这段时间来延长电池寿命
battery life and keep cool.
并保持设备凉爽
To make sure that we hit those
为了确保我们能够
targets, we track performance
达到这些目标 我们每天跟踪
every day.
帧速率的表现
So every day, we have an
我们每天都有
automation pass that goes
一个自动化的通道用来做这个
We look at key locations in the
我们看一看地图中的关键位置
map, and we capture performance.
并捕捉性能
So for instance, Tilted Towers,
例如 斜塔小镇
and Shifty Shafts, and all of
和矿井以及
the usual POIs that you're
你在堡垒之夜中所有
familiar with in Battle Royale.
熟悉的常见兴趣点
When one goes over budget, we
当超过预算时
know we need to dive in, figure
我们需要深入了解
out where performance is going,
了解性能进展情况
and optimize.
并对它进行优化
We also have daily 100-player
我们每天都会有一个 100 人
playtests where we capture the
的玩家测试
dynamic performance that you'll
用来捕捉你只能在游戏中看到的
only see during a game.
帧速率动态表现
We track key performance over
我们跟踪比赛时的
time for the match, and then we
帧速率的关键表现
can take a look at this
然后我们可以看一看
afterwards and see how it
看看它是如何工作的
performed, look for hitches,
如何寻找连结
stuff like that.
类似于这样的东西
And if something looks off, we
如果出现问题
can pull an instrumented profile
我们可以从设备中
off of the device, take a look
取出设备配置文件
at where time was going, and
查看时间到底去了哪里
figure out where we need to
找出我们需要优化的地方
We also support replays.
我们也支持重播
This is a feature in Unreal that
这是虚幻引擎的一个功能
allow us to go and replay that
它允许我们从玩家的角度去
match from a client perspective.
重放比赛
So we can play it over and over,
所以我们可以反复播放
analyze it, profile it, and even
分析它 解剖它
see how optimizations would have
甚至看看优化会
affected the client in that play
如何影响客户在游戏中的表现
Going to talk a little bit about
接下来我们专门
metal specifically.
讨论一下 Metal 技术
So we, on most devices, we have
我们在大多数设备上
2 cores, right, and so the way
都有 2 个核心 是的
we utilize that is we have a
所以我们使用的方式是
traditional game
我们有一个传统的游戏主线
thread/rendering thread split.
和渲染线程的拆分
On the game thread, we're doing
在游戏主线上
networking, simulation,
我们正在进行联网 模拟
animation, physics, and so on.
动画 物理等等工作
The rendering thread does all of
渲染线程执行
scene traversal, culling, and
所有场景遍历剔除并
calls.
发布所有 Metal API 调用
We also have an async thread.
我们也有一个异步线程
Mostly, it's handling streaming
大多数情况下 它处理
tasks -- texture streaming as
流式传输任务 纹理流式传输
well as level streaming.
以及级别流式传输
On newer devices where we have 2
在拥有 2 个快速内核
fast and 4 efficient cores, we
和 4 个高效内核的新设备上
add 3 more task threads and
我们增加了 3 个任务线程
enable some of the parallel
并启用了虚幻引擎中的一些
algorithms available in Unreal.
并行算法
So we take animation, put it,
所以我们采取动画在多帧
frames, CPU particles, physics,
CPU 粒子 物理等条件下
and so on, scene culling, a
进行模拟 场景剔除
couple other tasks.
以及其他一些任务
I mentioned draw calls earlier.
我之前提到过绘图调用
Draw calls were our main
绘图调用是我们的主要的
performance bottleneck, and this
表现瓶颈 而这实际上
is actually where Metal really
是 Metal 技术真正帮助
helped us out.
到我们的地方
We found Metal to be somewhere
我们发现使用 Metal 技术
on the order of 3 to 4 times
比使用 OpenGL 速度要
faster than OpenGL for what we
快 3 到 4 倍 这使我们
were doing, and that allowed us
能够在没有进行
to ship without doing a lot of
大量关于减少绘图调用的
aggressive work trying to reduce
积极工作的情况下进行交流
We did stuff to reduce draw
我们做了一些工作
calls, mostly pulling in cull
来减少绘图调用
distance on decorative objects
主要是在装饰物体上
as well as leveraging the
剔除距离 并利用
hierarchical level of detail
细节系统的层次结构
So here's an example.
这里是一个例子
This is one of those POIs that
这是我们一直追踪的
we tracked over time.
感兴趣的地点之一
If you're familiar with the
如果你对游戏非常熟悉
game, this is looking down on
那么这从悬崖上俯视斜塔小镇
Tilted Towers from a cliff and
的视角 也是我们在
was kind of our draw call hot
地图上的频繁使用绘图调用的地点
As you can see, it takes about
正如你所看到的
1300 draw calls to render this.
它大约需要 1300 次绘制调来渲染
This is just for the main pass.
这只是主要的传递
It doesn't include shadows, UI,
它不包括阴影
anything else that consumed draw
用户界面 其他任何
call time.
消耗绘图调用时间的内容
But Metal's really fast here.
但在这里使用 Metal 技术 真的可以变得很快
On an iPhone 8 Plus, we were
在 iPhone 8 Plus 上
able to chew through that in
我们能够在 5 毫秒的时间内完成
I mentioned hierarchical LOD.
我提到了分级 LOD
This is a feature we have in
这是虚幻引擎中的一项功能
Unreal where we can take
我们可以进行
multiple draw calls and generate
多次绘图调用并生成
a simplified version, a
一个简化版本
simplified mesh, as well as a
简化网格以及材质
material so that we can
以便我们可以在
basically render a
单个绘图调用中
representation of that area in a
渲染该区域的基本
single draw call.
表示形式
We use this for taking POIs and
我们使用它来获取
generating the simplified
我们感兴趣的地点
versions for rendering very,
生成用于渲染当距离非常
very far away.
非常遥远的简化版本
For instance, during the
例如 在跳伞期间
skydive, you can see the entire
你可以看到整个地图
In fact, when you're on the map,
事实上 当你在地图上时
you can get on a cliff or just
你可以爬上悬崖
build a very high tower of your
或者建造一座非常高的属于
own and see points of interest
自己的塔楼 你可以看到
from up to 2 kilometers away.
距离自己 2 公里远的风景
Digging into some of the other
接下来我将深入探讨
details on the Metal side, I
Metal 的其他细节
want to talk a little bit about
我想谈一谈一些关于
pipeline state objects.
管线状态对象的内容
This was something that took us
这是花一点时间
a little bit of time to get into
才能进入堡垒之夜的
a shippable state for Fortnite.
内部运输状态
You really want to minimize how
你非常想最小化
many PSOs you're creating while
你在框架中模拟游戏时
you're simulating the game
创建的管线状态对象数量
If you create too many, it's
如果你创造的太多
very easy to hitch and create a
就很容易造成故障
poor player experience.
并造成糟糕的游戏体验
So first of all, follow best
首先 请遵循最佳
practices, right.
实践准则 对
Compile your functions offline,
离线编译你的函数
build your library offline, and
离线构建你的函数库
pull all of your functions into
并将所有函数提取到
a single library.
单个函数库中
But you really want to make sure
但是你实在是想
you create all of your PSOs at
确保在加载时创建所有
load time.
管线状态对象
But what do you do if you can't
但是如果你不能这样做 你会怎么办
So for us, the permutation
所以对于我们来说
matrix is just crazy.
置换矩阵只是一个疯狂的行为
There's way too many for us to
对于我们来说
realistically create at load
在加载时 实际创建的方式太多了
time.
我们有多个开发者创作的着色器
shaders -- thousands of them --
数千个着色器
multiple lighting scenarios
基于阴影级联数量
based on number of shadow
的多个照明场景等
cascades and so on, different
不同渲染目标格式
render target formats, MSAA.
MSAA
The list goes on.
名单有很长
We tried to minimize
我们尽可能减少
permutations where we could, and
排列组合的数量
this does help.
这确实有帮助
Sometimes a dynamic branch is
有时候动态分支比
good enough and better than
创建静态排列表现
creating a static permutation,
更好 但有时候就不行
What we had to do is we decided
我们必须要做的是
to identify the most common
决定可能需要的
subset that we're likely to
最常见的子集
need, and we create those at
并且在载入时创建这些子集
We don't try to create
我们不试图创造一切
The way we achieved this is we
我们实现这一目标
created an automation pass where
的方式是创建了一个自动化的管线
we basically flew a camera
我们基本上是在环境中
through the environment and
安装了一台摄像机
recorded all of the PSOs that we
并记录了所有的
actually needed to render the
需要实际渲染环境的
environment.
管线状态对象
Then, during our daily
然后 在我们的日常
playtests, we harvested any PSOs
测试中 我们获得了
that were created that were not
所有未被该自动化管线
caught by that automation pass.
所捕获的管线状态对象
The automation pass also
自动化管线也
catches, like, cosmetics, and
可以捕获像美化
effects from firing different
和发射不同武器的效果
weapons, and so on.
等等对象
We take all of that information
我们把从自动化
from automation and from the
和游戏测试中获取
playtest, combine it into a
所有这些信息组合成一个列表
That's what we create at load
这是我们在加载时创建的
time, and that's what we ship
也是我们随游戏一起运行的内容
It's not perfect, but we find
这并不完美 但我们发现
that the number of PSOs we
我们在运行时创建的
create at runtime is in the
管线状态对象数量
single digits for any given play
平均为任何游戏部分创建的个位数
And so players don't experience
所以玩家不会遇到任何
any hitching from PSO creation.
生成管线状态对象的麻烦
Resource allocation.
资源分配
So basically, creating and
所以基本上 创建和
deleting resources is expensive
删除资源是昂贵的
or can be expensive.
或可能是昂贵的
It's kind of like, think of
这有点像 想一想
[inaudible].
[ 音质不清晰 ]
You really want to minimize the
你非常想尽可能
number of [inaudible] you're
减少你每帧
making per frame.
制作的 [ 音质不清晰 ] 数量
You really don't want to be
你非常不想
creating and destroying a lot of
动态创建和销毁
resources on the fly, but when
大量资源 但是当你
you're streaming in content
动态地在内容中进行流式传输时
dynamically, when you have a lot
当你有很多
of movable objects, some of this
可移动的对象时
just isn't possible to avoid.
有些操作是无法避免的
So what we did for buffers is we
所以我们对缓冲区所做的
just used buffer suballocation
只是使用缓冲区子分配
-- basically, a bend allocation
基本上是一种不直接分配的策略
Upfront, we allocate a big
首先 我们分配一个大缓冲区
buffer, and then we suballocate
然后我们将大缓冲区
small chunks back to the engine
分成小块并重新分配回引擎
to avoid asking Metal for new
以回避始终向 Metal
buffers all the time.
请求新的缓冲区的操作
And this ended up helping a lot.
而这最终起到了很大的作用
We also leveraged programmable
我们还利用可编程混合
blending to reduce the number of
来减少解析
resolves and restores and the
和恢复次数
amount of memory bandwidth we
以及我们使用的内存带宽量
Specifically, the main use case
具体来说 我们对此的
we have for this is anywhere we
主要使用场景是任何我们
need access to scene depth, so
需要访问场景深度的地方
things like soft particle
例如软粒子混合
blending or projected decals.
或投影贴图
What we do is during the forward
我们所做的是在
pass, we write our linear depth
正向传递期间将线性深度
to the alpha channel.
写入 Alpha 通道
And then, during our decal and
然后 在我们
translucent passes, all we need
的贴图和半透明化的过程中
to do is use programmable
我们需要做的就是
blending to read that alpha
使用可编程混合来
channel back, and we can use
读取该 Alpha 通道
depth without having ever had to
并且可以使用深度信息
resolve the depth buffer to main
而不必将深度缓冲区解析到主内存
We also use it to improve the
我们也使用它来提高
quality of MSAA.
MSAA 的质量
As I mentioned, we do HDR
正如我所提到的
rendering, and a-- just an MSAA
我们进行 HDR 渲染 但是
resolve of HDR can still lead to
仅仅是 HDR 的 MSAA 解析仍然会
very aliased edges.
导致非常参差的边缘
Think of cases where you have a
想想你有一个
very, very bright sky and a
非常非常明亮的天空和
very, very dark foreground.
非常非常黑暗的前视图的情况
Just doing a box filter over
这时只需要做一个
that is, basically, if 1 of
盒式过滤器就可以了 基本上
those subsamples is incredibly
是说如果其中一个子样本
bright and the others are
非常明亮 其他样本非常
incredibly dark, the result is
黑暗 那么结果将是
going to be an incredibly bright
一个令人难以置信的明亮像素
pixel.
当色调映射时
something close to white.
它会接近白色
You end up with edges that don't
你最终会看到边缘看起来
look anti-aliased at all.
完全没有反锯齿的样子
So our solution to this was to
因此 我们的解决方案
do a pre tone map over all of
是对所有 MSAA 样本执行
the MSAA samples, then perform
预先的色调映射 然后
the normal MSAA resolve, and
执行正常的 MSAA 分辨率
then the first postprocessing
然后第一个后处理通道
pass just reverses that pre tone
只是反转之前的预映射图
We use programmable blending for
我们使用可编程混合进行
the pre tone map pass.
预色调贴图过程
Otherwise, we'd have to resolve
否则 我们必须将
the entire MSAA color buffer to
整个 MSAA 颜色缓冲区
memory and read it back in,
解析为内存并将其读回
which would be unaffordable.
这是我们负担不起的
Looking forward to some of the
接下来我将展望一下
work we'd like to do in the
未来我们希望在
future with Metal, parallel
Metal 中进行的一些工作并行渲染
rendering.
所以在 macOS 上 我们
creating command buffers in
确实支持并行地创建
parallel.
命令缓冲区
On iOS, we'd really need to
在 iOS 上 我们需要
support parallel command
支持并行命令
encoders for this to be
的编码器才能使用它
A lot of our drawing ends up
我们的很多绘制
happening in the main forward
最终都会发生在
pass, and so it's important to
主要正向传递中 因此将其
parallelize that.
并行化非常重要
I think it would be very
我认为 看到
interesting to sort of see the
并行渲染对单片快速
effects of parallel rendering on
内核的影响和
a monolithic, fast core versus
在高端设备高效内核上使用
what we had for parallel command
并行命令编码器
encoders on the efficient cores
的效果进行比较会
on higher-end devices.
非常有趣
Could be some interesting
这可能会在
results in terms of battery
电池使用方面产生
usage.
一些有趣的结果
Metal heaps.
Metal 堆
So we'd like to replace our
所以我们希望用 Metal 堆
buffer suballocation with Metal
来代替我们的缓冲区
heaps -- first, because it'll
子分配 首先
just simply our code, but
因为它只是简单的代码
second, because we can also use
其次 因为我们也可以
it for textures.
把它用于纹理
We still see an occasional hitch
我们由于纹理流式传输
due to texture streaming because
仍然偶尔会遇到麻烦
we're obviously creating and
因为我们会在显式地
destroying textures on the fly
动态地创建和销毁纹理
as we bring textures in and out
就像把纹理不断的在内存里进行读写
Being able to use heaps for this
使用堆可以摆脱
will get rid of those hitches.
那些困境
For us, we just, it's, the work
对我们来说
we have in front of us to make
我们面前的工作就是
that possible is setting up
要在不同的通道
precise fencing between the
之间设置精确的栅栏
So we need to know explicitly if
所以我们需要明确地
a resource is being read or
知道资源是否被顶点
written by a vertex or pixel
或像素着色器在
shader across different passes,
不同的过程中读取或写入
and it requires some reworking
并且这需要我们
of some of our renderer to make
对一些渲染器进行一些修改才能实现
And of course, continue to push
当然 也要继续推动 iOS 上的图形学
the high end of graphics on iOS.
向高端的发展
Last year at WWDC, we showed
去年在 WWDC 上
what was possible by bringing
我们展示了将我们的
our desktop-class forward
桌面级正向渲染器
renderer to high-end iOS
引入高端 iOS 设备的可能性
devices, and we continue, we
并且我们继续在做这件事
want to continue pushing that
我们希望继续在 iOS 上
bar on iOS, continuing to bring
推动这一目标
desktop-class features to iOS
继续为 iOS 带来
and looking for opportunities to
桌面级功能并寻找机会
unify our desktop renderer with
将我们的桌面渲染器与
the iOS renderer.
iOS 渲染器统一起来
And with that, I'll hand it back
然后 我要把场地交回给 Michael
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; So Metal is low overhead out
&gt;&gt; Metal 技术
of the box, but rendering many
的开销很低
objects efficiently can require
但可以通过多线程
multithreading.
高效地渲染许多对象
Metal is built to take advantage
Metal 技术是
of all the GPU, all the CPUs in
为了充分利用我们系统中的所有 GPU
our systems.
和所有 CPU 而创建的
Metal is also really accessible,
Metal 技术也是
but advanced rendering sometimes
真正可访问的 但高级渲染
requires explicit control.
有时需要显式控制
Metal provides this control when
当你需要内存管理和
you need it for memory
GPU 并行性时
management and GPU parallelism.
Metal 技术提供了这种控制
We also introduced indirect
我们还引入了间接命令缓冲区
command buffers, our brand-new
这是我们的全新功能
feature that lets you move
它可以让你将命令
command generation entirely to
生成完全移至 GPU
the GPU, freeing the CPU for
释放 CPU 来执行其他任务
Together with argument buffers,
与参数缓冲区一起
these features provide a
这些功能为 GPU 驱动的
complete solution to GPU-driven
管线提供了完整的解决方案
And finally, Metal lets you
最后 Metal 允许你
leverage the advanced
利用 A11 GPU 的
architecture of the A11 GPU to
高级架构来优化
optimize many rendering
渲染技术
techniques for both maximum
以实现最佳性能
performance and extended
和更长的游戏时间
For more information, please
想要了解更多信息
visit our website, and be sure
请访问我们的网站 并确保
to visit us in tomorrow's lab.
访问我们明天的实验室 谢谢
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]